Guide to the David Peck Todd Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Scientific Subjects and Exhibitions, (1878-1939); Series II; 21.75 linear feet (54 boxes)
  - Eclipse of 22 Dec 1889, Angola; Voyage of Pensacola (Box 36)
    - Reports:
      - On solar corona, by Frank H. Bigelow (Box 37, Folder 249)
    - U. S. Coast and Geodetic Survey (Box 37, Folder 250)
    - Newspaper report: Herman S. Davis, A Seven Months Cruise (Box 37, Folder 251)
    - Reports:
      - Eben J. Loomis, An Eclipse Party in Africa (Box 37, Folder 252)
      - By others: reminiscences (Box 37, Folder 253)
    - Research material for David P. Todd lecture on St. Helena (Box 37, Folder 254)
    - Newspaper reports (Box 38, Folder 255)
    - Memorabilia:
      - Mss., etc. (Box 38, Folder 256)
      - Printed (Box 38, Folder 257)
      - Magazine articles (Box 38, Folder 258)
      - Local newspapers (Box 38, Folder 259)
      - Music programs (Box 38, Folder 260)
    - Waterspout: photos and description (Box 38, Folder 261)
    - Newspaper clippings on expedition (Box 38, Folder 262)
    - Perforated sheet of pneumatic commutator (Box 39, Folder 263)
    - Photos:
      - U. S. S. Pensacola (Box 39, Folder 264)
      - Scientific apparatus (Box 39, Folder 265)
      - Cape Ledo, eclipse camp (Box 39, Folder 266)
      - Ascension (Box 39, Folder 267)
      - Cape Verde Islands (Box 40, Folder 268)
      - St. Helena (Box 40, Folder 269-270)
      - W. Africa (Box 40, Folder 271)
      - Unidentified (Box 40, Folder 272)
        See: Photographs and Glass Plates, Series VII; St. Helena, South Africa, Africa
  - Eclipse of 9 Aug 1896, Esashi, Japan
    - Legal-personal (Box 41, Folder 274)
    - Maps (Box 41, Folder 275)
    - Geological surveys and maps, 1874-1875 (Box 41, Folder 276)
    - Books, articles for expedition (Box 41, Folder 277)
    - Apparatus: description, lists, photos, diagrams (Box 41, Folder 278)
    - Correspondence:
      - 25 May 1895-9 August 1896 (Box 41, Folder 279)
      - Re: public library, Esashi, 19 September 1896—27 December 1955 (Box 41, Folder 280)
      - 11 August 1896—15 January 1899 (Box 41, Folder 281)
    - Scientific notes, David P. Todd and others (Box 41, Folder 282)
    - Sketch of corona by E. A. T[hompson] (Box 41, Folder 283)
    - Report by Mabel Loomis Todd; sketches, notes (Box 41, Folder 284)
    - Report on voyage and eclipse by Harriet P. James (Mrs. Arthur C.) (Box 42, Folder 285)
    - Report on expedition by others (Box 42, Folder 286)
    - Photos:
      - Station at Esashi; members of expedition and others (Box 42, Folder 287)
      - Photos and diagrams of astronomical instruments and phenomena (Box 42, Folder 288)
      - Voyage, Japanese life, people (largely unidentified), Hawaii (Box 42, Folder 289)
      - Places on voyages, Japanese life, people (largely unidentified) (Box 42, Folder 290)
      - Album of expedition at Esashi; instruments, annotated by David P. Todd (Box 42, Folder 291)
        See: box 120, scrapbook 5
        See also: Todd-Bingham Picture Collection, MS 496E, Series II, Vol. 19
    - Public library at Esashi: book lists, memorabilia (Box 43, Folder 293)
    - Imperial Sake Cup Award, 1897 (Box 43, Folder 294)
    - Newspaper reports—English (Box 43, Folder 295)
    - Newspaper reports on expedition, Japanese (Box 43, Folder 296)
    - Report by "H. H. T." in The Observatory (Box 43, Folder 297)
    - Memorabilia:
      - Finances (Box 43, Folder 298)
      - Artifacts (Box 43, Folder 299)
      - Mss. (Box 44, Folder 300)
      - Printed memorabilia of the Expedition (Box 44, Folder 301)
      - Printed memorabilia of Japan (Box 44, Folder 302)
      - Calling cards (Box 44, Folder 303)
      - Japanese printed and mss. (unidentified) (Box 44, Folder 304)
      - Local newspapers, English (Box 44, Folder 305)
      - Later correspondence and memorabilia, 1909-1936 (Box 44, Folder 306)
      - Local newspapers, Japanese (Box 44, Folder 307)
  - Eclipse of 28 May 1900, Tripoli (Box 45)
    - Legal-personal (Box 45, Folder 308)
    - Maps (Box 45, Folder 309)
    - Scientific material used in preparation (Box 45, Folder 310)
    - Correspondence, 28 December 1899-20 November 1905 (Box 45, Folder 311)
    - Reports on eclipse by David P. Todd (Box 45, Folder 312)
    - Report on eclipse by others (Box 45, Folder 313)
    - Apparatus for expedition (Box 45, Folder 314)
    - Photos:
      - Astronomical (Box 45, Folder 315)
      - Apparatus (Box 45, Folder 316)
      - People (Box 45, Folder 317)
      - Nice, Tripoli, etc., local color (Box 45, Folder 318)
      - Local color (Box 45, Folder 319)
      - Negatives, duplicates (Box 46, Folder 320)
    - Journal by David P. Todd on trip (Box 46, Folder 321)
    - Newspaper reports (Box 46, Folder 322)
    - Article on expedition in Amherst Quarterly (Box 46, Folder 323)
    - Memorabilia:
      - Mss. (Box 46, Folder 324)
      - Financial (Box 46, Folder 325)
      - Printed (Box 46, Folder 326)
      - Calling cards, photo album from trip (Box 46, Folder 327)
  - Eclipse of 18 May 1901, Sing Kep
    - Maps (Box 47, Folder 328)
    - Legal-personal (Box 47, Folder 329)
    - Report on Panay (Box 47, Folder 330)
    - Correspondence, 5 February 1901, 12 May 1903 (Box 47, Folder 331)
    - Scientific notes by David P. Todd (Box 47, Folder 332)
    - Reports on eclipse by others, including Mabel Todd (Box 47, Folder 333)
    - Photos:
      - Astronomical (Box 47, Folder 334)
      - Members of the expedition; apparatus at the station; ship (Box 47, Folder 335)
      - Algiers, Azores, Japan, Malta, Naples, Philippines, Port Said (Box 47, Folder 336)
      - Shanghai, Siam (Box 47, Folder 337)
      - Singapore (Box 47, Folder 338)
      - Sing Kep (Box 47, Folder 339)
      - Chinese coolies in mine at Sing Kep; other mine pictures (Box 47, Folder 340)
      - Unidentified (Box 48, Folder 341)
      - Voyage, Singapore, unidentified (Box 48, Folder 342)
      - Album (Box 48, Folder 343)
    - Reports on eclipse in scientific journals (Box 48, Folder 344-345)
    - Newspaper reports (Box 48, Folder 346)
    - Memorabilia:
      - Mss. (Box 48, Folder 347)
      - Financial (Box 48, Folder 348)
      - Printed (Box 48, Folder 349)
      - Singapore (Box 49, Folder 350)
      - Printed matter on straits settlements (Box 49, Folder 351)
      - Printed (Box 49, Folder 352)
      - Calling cards (Box 49, Folder 353)
      - Local newspapers (Box 49, Folder 354-355)
    - Later material (Box 49, Folder 356)
  - Eclipse of 30 Aug 1905, Tripoli
    - Legal-financial (Box 50, Folder 357)
    - Scientific materials used in preparation (Box 50, Folder 358)
    - Correspondence, 20 March-23 September 1905 (Box 50, Folder 359)
    - Scientific notes by David P. Todd and others (Box 50, Folder 360)
    - Sketches of corona by various hands (Box 50, Folder 361)
    - Photos:
      - Eclipse (Box 50, Folder 362)
      - Expedition members and apparatus (Box 50, Folder 363)
      - Album (Box 50, Folder 364)
      - [untitled] (Box 51, Folder 365)
      - Tripoli (Box 51, Folder 366)
      - Negatives (Box 51, Folder 367)
    - Report by David P. Todd in Journal of Science (Box 51, Folder 368)
    - Reports in scientific journals of the eclipse (Box 51, Folder 369)
    - Newspaper clippings:
      - Expedition (Box 51, Folder 370)
      - Eclipse (Box 51, Folder 371)
    - Memorabilia:
      - Mss. (Box 51, Folder 372)
      - Calling cards (Box 51, Folder 373)
      - Finances (Box 51, Folder 374)
      - Printed (Box 51, Folder 375)
      - Local newspapers (Box 51, Folder 376)
  - Opposition of Mars, 1907, Chile
    - Legal-personal (Box 52, Folder 377)
    - Maps (Box 52, Folder 378)
    - Preparatory scientific material (Box 52, Folder 379)
    - Correspondence, 6 February-27 May 1907, 1 June 1907-21 January 1911 (Box 52, Folder 380-381)
    - David P. Todd: journals, 3 April-13 August 1907, 20-22 August 1907 (Box 52, Folder 382)
    - Correspondence of Mabel L. Todd (Box 53, Folder 383)
    - Shipment of apparatus and baggage (Box 53, Folder 384)
    - David P. Todd:
      - Scientific notes (Box 53, Folder 385)
      - Computation of annular eclipse, 10 July 1907 (Box 53, Folder 386)
      - General notes (Box 53, Folder 387)
    - Mabel L. Todd notes on Chile, Peru, Inca astronomy (Box 53, Folder 388)
    - Reports, sketches of Mars by others (including Mabel L. Todd) (Box 53, Folder 389)
    - Report by Albert J. Ilse (Box 53, Folder 390)
    - Photos:
      - Astronomical (Box 53, Folder 391)
      - Apparatus (Box 53, Folder 392)
      - Chile, Panama, Peru (Box 53, Folder 393)
      - Todds, unidentified people (Box 53, Folder 394)
      - Earthquake, 1906 (Box 53, Folder 395)
        [Folder noted as missing, 10/2006]
      - List of photos and photographers on expedition (Box 53, Folder 396)
      - Negatives (Box 53, Folder 397-398)
      - Negatives (Box 54, Folder 399)
    - Newspaper reports on expedition, Mar—May 1907, June 1907, July 1907 (Box 54, Folder 400-402)
    - Newspaper reports, August-December 1907 (Box 54, Folder 403)
    - Magazine reports, May 1907-March 1908 (Box 54, Folder 404)
    - Photo album on nitrate works, Vistas de las Faenas y Puertos Salitreros (Box 54, Folder 405)
    - Memorabilia:
      - Finances (Box 55, Folder 406)
      - Mss. (Box 55, Folder 407)
      - Printed stationery samples of expedition (Box 55, Folder 408)
      - Menus, programs, advertisements, posters (Box 55, Folder 409)
      - Calling cards (Box 55, Folder 410)
      - Printed, on cultural life (Box 55, Folder 411)
      - Magazines, June 1907-February 1908 (Box 55, Folder 412)
      - Local newspapers (Box 56, Folder 413-414)
      - Playing cards; calendar (Box 56, Folder 415)
      - Devotional pictures (Box 56, Folder 416)
    - Material on Panama Canal (Box 56, Folder 417)
    - Material on sodium nitrate (Box 56, Folder 418)
  - Eclipse of 21 Aug 1914, Russia
    - Legal-personal (Box 57, Folder 419)
    - Maps (Box 57, Folder 420)
    - Map of Russian Empire, 1883
      See: Oversize
    - Preliminary notes by David P. Todd (Box 57, Folder 421)
    - Correspondence:
      - 20 May 1912-31 May 1914 (Box 57, Folder 422)
      - 8 June-10 August 1914 (Box 57, Folder 423)
      - 21 August 1914-19 December 1921 (Box 57, Folder 424)
    - Scientific notes by David P. Todd (Box 57, Folder 425)
    - Photos:
      - Scientific; unidentified astronomer [?] (Box 57, Folder 426)
      - Photos (Box 57, Folder 427)
    - Report by David P. Todd for, December 1914 (Box 57, Folder 428)
      See also box 81, folder 187
    - Newspaper reports on expedition (Box 57, Folder 429)
    - Memorabilia:
      - Mss. by Mabel L. Todd (Box 57, Folder 430)
      - Mss. (Box 57, Folder 431)
      - Drug prescriptions for Mabel L. Todd (Box 57, Folder 432)
      - Financial (Box 57, Folder 433)
      - Calling cards (Box 58, Folder 434)
      - Printed, of Scandinavia (Box 58, Folder 435)
      - Printed (Box 58, Folder 436)
      - Printed: programs, menus, tickets, advertisements (Box 58, Folder 437)
        See: memorabilia: oversize
      - Printed: programs, menus, advertisements (Box 58, Folder 438)
      - Printed: scientific and background material (Box 58, Folder 439)
      - Printed: war pamphlets (Box 58, Folder 440)
      - Local newspapers (Box 58, Folder 441)
  - Eclipse of 8 Jun 1918, U.S.
    - Map of path of eclipse across U. S. (Box 59, Folder 442)
      General
      See also Box 59b.
    - Map of the path of the sun, 8 June 1918 (Box 59b)
      See Box 59, Folder 442.
    - Preparatory notes by David P. Todd (Box 59, Folder 443)
    - Preparatory material on weather (Box 59, Folder 444)
    - Correspondence with sky observers (Box 59, Folder 445)
    - Preliminary reports of the sky 1893-1917 by many observers; collected by David P. Todd (Box 59, Folder 446)
    - Instructions to observers by David P. Todd (Box 59, Folder 447)
    - Reports on eclipse (Box 59, Folder 448)
    - Newspaper reports (Box 59, Folder 449)
  - Eclipse of 29 May 1919, Bahamas, Brazil
    - Personal and legal papers (Box 59a, Folder 449a)
    - Correspondence (Box 59a, Folder 449b)
    - Newspaper reports (Box 59a, Folder 449c)
  - Bahamas Expedition Re: Observation of Mars, 1922
    - Correspondence, 8 May-22 October 1922 (Box 60, Folder 450)
    - David P. Todd notes (Box 60, Folder 451)
    - Newspaper reports (Box 60, Folder 452)
    - Memorabilia (Box 60, Folder 453)
    - Correspondence (Box 60, Folder 454)
  - Eclipse of 24 Jan 1925, U.S.
    - Correspondence, 1917, 1923-1925 (Box 61, Folder 455-456)
    - Maps, charts (Box 61, Folder 457)
    - Preparatory material (Box 61, Folder 458)
    - Preliminary reports (Box 61, Folder 459)
    - Finances (Box 61, Folder 460)
    - Reports: David P. Todd and others (Box 61, Folder 461)
    - Report on industrial aspects (Box 61, Folder 462)
    - Photos (Box 61, Folder 463)
    - Cut made from sketch and photo of painting of eclipse by Aleth Bjorn (Box 61, Folder 464)
    - News reports by David P. Todd (Box 61, Folder 465)
    - News reports re: David P. Todd (Box 61, Folder 466)
    - Newspaper reports on eclipse (Box 61, Folder 467)
    - Magazine reports (Box 61, Folder 468)
  - Eclipse of 31 Aug 1932, Portland, Maine
    - Maps and charts (Box 62, Folder 469-470)
    - Correspondence re: pilot chart of 1932 (Box 62, Folder 471)
    - Correspondence:
      - December 1924-December 1931 (Box 62, Folder 472)
      - 1 January 1932-31 August 1932 (Box 62, Folder 473)
      - 4 September-14 October 1932 (Box 62, Folder 474)
    - Preliminary material by observers (Box 63, Folder 475)
    - Sketches and notes by Millicent Todd Bingham (Box 63, Folder 476)
    - Articles on eclipse of 1932 by David P. Todd
      See: box 84, folder 224
    - Photos (Box 63, Folder 477)
    - Memorabilia:
      - Mss. (Box 63, Folder 478)
      - Printed (Box 63, Folder 479)
    - Magazine articles (Box 63, Folder 480)
    - Newspapers (Box 64, Folder 481-485)
    - Search for Trans-Neptunian planet: correspondence, 1881-1897 (Box 65, Folder 486)
    - Observation of Saturn's rings: correspondence, 1911-1913 (Box 65, Folder 487)
    - Observation of Mars: scientific drawing, 1909 (Box 66, Folder 488)
    - 1909 Signalling Mars: scrapbook of newspaper clippings, newspaper clippings, memorabilia
      See: box 120, scrapbook 6
    - Mars Signals: newspaper reports, 1909, circa 1900?—28 June 1909 (Box 66, Folder 489)
    - Signals From Mars: correspondence, 1909, 1918, 1924, 1932 (Box 66, Folder 490)
    - Proposed expedition to Peru re: Mars correspondence, 1924 (Box 66, Folder 491)
  - Mars Signals, 1924
    - Notes:
      - By David P. Todd, 1914, 1924 (Box 66, Folder 492)
      - By others (Box 66, Folder 493)
      - On radio camera (Box 66, Folder 494)
    - Radio signal tape, 22 August 1924 (Box 66, Folder 495)
    - Photos of radio signals, 22 August 1924 (Box 66, Folder 496)
    - Newspaper reports, 1921-24 August 1924, October 1924-May 1929 (Box 66, Folder 497-498)
- Writings (including correspondence with publishers), (1873-1933); Series III; 5.75 linear feet (20 boxes)
  This series is arranged according to the type of writing, and its status as published or unpublished work. With each book title is the material related to its production: correspondence with the publishers, notes, drafts, illustrations, proofs, advertising and promotion materials, and reviews, arranged in that order. Not every book has material in each of these categories. Letters to publishers or editors and research materials about articles are also placed with the work.
  Books
  1. Books, published
  2. Books, unpublished
  Articles
  1. Articles, published. These include both scientific astronomical articles and popular articles, together spanning the period 1873 to 1933.
  2. Articles for the Nation, 1880-1915
  3. Miscellaneous writings: book reviews, letters to the editor, newspaper articles, 1883-1932.
  4. Unpublished articles, drafts from 1878 to 1932.
  notes and Scrapbooks
  1. Unpublished and undated notes on non-scientific subjects. For notes on projects which were formulated and followed through to some degree, see Series II, Scientific Subjects and Expeditions.
  2. Oversize scrapbook with clippings of published articles by David Peck Todd from 1888 to 1907.
  3. Microfilm of articles published between 1888 and 1907. See Historical Manuscript Film 67.
  - Books, published
    - Columbian Knowledge Series
      - Vol. I, ed. David P. Todd. "Total Eclipses" by Mabel Loomis Todd: review (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - Vol. II, ed. David P. Todd. Public Libraries by William I. Fletcher: reviews; poster (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - Vol. III, ed. David P. Todd. Handbook of Arctic... by A. W. Greely: reviews, notices, 1896 (Box 67, Folder 3)
      - Vol. III, ed. David P. Todd. Handbook of Arctic... by A. W. Greely, 1896 (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1894-1895
    - New Astronomy For Beginners
      - Correspondence with publisher American Book Co., 1897 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Contract; royalties, 1897 (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - David P. Todd notes and draft, 1897 (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - Illustrations, diagrams for reference, 1897 (Box 68, Folder 8)
      - Illustrations, 1897 (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - Illustrations, proofs, 1897 (Box 68, Folder 10)
      - Advertising material, 1897 (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - Soliciting of reviews, 1897 (Box 68, Folder 12)
      - Letters commenting on book, 1897 (Box 68, Folder 13)
      - Notices and reviews, 1897 (Box 68, Folder 14)
      - Reviews, 1897 (Box 69, Folder 15)
      - Japanese ed., 1897 (Box 69, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence re: Hungarian ed., 1897 (Box 69, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence, 1923 (Box 69, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence re: 1925 ed. (Box 69, Folder 19)
      - Addenda et corrigenda, 22nd edition, 1925 (Box 69, Folder 20)
      - Correspondence re: 1941 revision (Box 69, Folder 21)
    - Stars and Telescopes, 1899
      - Correspondence, 1899-1920 (Box 70, Folder 22)
      - Contract, royalties, 1899 (Box 70, Folder 23)
      - "All About the Ruddy Planet" (Mars) part of S&T, 1899 (Box 70, Folder 24)
      - Illustrations (Box 70, Folder 25)
      - Draft index (Box 70, Folder 26)
      - Proofs of portion of text; jacket, binding, 1899 (Box 70, Folder 27)
      - Advertising, 1899 (Box 70, Folder 28)
      - Reviews and notices, 1899 (Box 70, Folder 29)
      - Reviews and notices from scrapbook, 1899 (Box 70, Folder 30)
    - Astronomy, The Science …
      - Correspondence:
        - With Serviss, Garrett P., 1920 (Box 71, Folder 31)
        - With Colliers:
          - 1921 (Box 71, Folder 32)
          - 1922-1925 (Box 71, Folder 33)
        - Re: 1939 ed. (Box 71, Folder 34)
      - Manuscripts:
        - Mss. 1 (Box 71, Folder 35)
        - Mss. 2 (Box 71, Folder 36)
        - Mss. 3 (Box 71, Folder 37)
        - Typed manuscript 1, 1921, 1922 (Box 72, Folder 38)
        - Typed manuscript 2, 1921, 1922 (Box 72, Folder 39)
      - notes, section of printed dummy, pp. 34-288, 1921, 1922 (Box 72, Folder 40)
      - Notices and reviews, 1922 (Box 72, Folder 41)
    - Proposed Books, 1897-1903 (Box 73, Folder 42)
      - Riddle of Mars, 1908
        - Correspondence with publisher, 1907-1916 (Box 73, Folder 43)
        - Xerox of most complete copy, 1908 (Box 73, Folder 44)
        - Typed mss. of most complete copy, 1908 (Box 73, Folder 45)
        - 12 chapters—typescript, 1908 (Box 73, Folder 46)
        - Handwritten Drafts:
          - Chapters I-VIII (not complete), 1908 (Box 73, Folder 47)
          - Chapters IX-XVI (not complete), 1908 (Box 73, Folder 48)
          - Chapters XVII-XXXVIII (not complete), 1908 (Box 73, Folder 49)
        - notes, photos, illustrations, 1908 (Box 73, Folder 50)
        - Reference material—scientific; popular literary, 1908 (Box 73, Folder 51)
      - The Apple Culturist, revised by David Peck Todd, 1926
        - notes and correspondence (Box 74, Folder 52)
        - Revised copy (Box 74, Folder 53)
        - Printed pamphlets—Department of Agriculture (Box 74, Folder 54)
    - Scrapbooks (3): (Box 75)
      - 1876-1890 (2 copies) (Box 75)
      - 1890-1893 (1 copy) (Box 75)
  - Articles, published
    - "Concerning a Telescope of Unlimited Power," Scientific American, 13 December 1873 (Box 76, Folder 55)
    - "Observations of the Phenomena of Jupiter's Satellites," Astronomische Nachrichten, 1875 (Box 76, Folder 56)
      - notes (Box 76, Folder 57)
    - "Continuation of de Damoiseau's Tables …"
      - notes 1, 1878 (Box 76, Folder 58)
      - notes 2, 1876 (Box 76, Folder 59)
      - Two bound copies, 1876 (Box 76, Folder 60)
      - Paper edition, 1876 (Box 76, Folder 61)
      - Page proofs, 1876 (Box 76, Folder 61a)
      - Manuscript draft and tables (Box 76a, Folder 61b)
    - "Occultations of Planets Observed at Washington, 1876 and 1877," Astronomische Nachrichten (Box 76a, Folder 62)
    - "Remarks on Observations of the Satellites of Jupiter," The Observatory (reprint), 20 September 1877 (Box 76a, Folder 63)
    - "Observations of the Transit of Mercury, 1878, May 6, Including a Systematic Search for a Satellite …," reprint, proofs, 1879 August (Box 76a, Folder 64)
    - "Report on the Total Solar Eclipse of 1878, July 29," from App III to Washington Observations for 1876, 1880 (Box 76a, Folder 65)
    - "Solar Parallax from the Velocity of Light," American Journal of Science (reprint), 1880 January (Box 76a, Folder 66)
      - Correspondence (Box 76a, Folder 67)
    - "On a Mechanical Attachment …," Proceedings of the American Academy of the Arts and Sciences (reprint 2), 12 May 1880 (Box 76a, Folder 68)
    - "Preliminary Account of a Speculative and Practical Search for a Trans-Neptunian Planet," correspondence, American Journal of Science, 1880 September (Box 76a, Folder 69)
    - "Preliminary Account of a Speculative and Practical Search for a Trans-Neptunian Planet," American Journal of Science, 1880 September (Box 76a, Folder 70)
    - "On the Use of the Electric Telegraph…," Proceedings of AAAS, reprints, notes, 12 January 1881 (Box 76a, Folder 71)
    - "On the Use of the Electric Telegraph…", The Observatory, 1 July 1881 (Box 76a, Folder 72)
    - "On the Solar Parallax as Derived from the American Photographs of the Transit of Venus, 1874, Dec 8-9," American Journal of Science
      - Correspondence, 1881 June (Box 77, Folder 73)
      - Reprints (Box 77, Folder 74)
      - In Copernicus, 1881 (Box 77, Folder 75)
    - "An Account of Observations of the Transit of Venus, 1882 …," Science, 1883 Feb correspondence (Box 77, Folder 76)
      - American Journal of Science, notes and offprints, 1883 February (Box 77, Folder 77)
      - The Observatory, 1 March 1883 (Box 77, Folder 78)
    - "On the Observations of the Transit of Venus, 1882, Dec. 5-6, made at the Lick Observatory…", Monthly Notices, R.A.S., 1883 March (Box 77, Folder 79)
    - "A Comparison of Leverrier's Tables of Uranus and Neptune with those by Newcomb of the Same Planets," Copernicus, 1883 (Box 77, Folder 80)
    - "Micrometric Observations of Jupiter's Third Satellite," (Box 77, Folder 81)
    - "On the Course of the Corrections to the Heliocentric Longitudes," Proceedings—American Association for the Advancement of Science, correspondence, 1884 (Box 77, Folder 81)
    - "Physical Training at Amherst," Science, 30 January 1885
      - Correspondence (Box 77, Folder 82)
      - Reprint, 30 January 1885 (Box 77, Folder 83)
    - "The British Nautical Almanac," Science, 27 February 1885 (Box 77, Folder 84)
    - "Telescopic Search for the Transneptunian Planet," Proceedings, AAAS, offprints; proofs of cuts, 1885 June (Box 77, Folder 85)
    - "The Lick Observatory …," Science, 4 September 1885
      - Offprints, bound copy, typed abstract (Box 77, Folder 86)